<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/categories/ionic-framework/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/categories/ionic-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Million Words Social Network built using Ionic Framework</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/ionic-million-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 12:53:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/ionic-million-words/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to learn more javascript frameworks after getting a glimpse of React-Native and basic understanding of javascript
this time my focus was to learn a framwork that will help me in learning web-development too, So I came across AngularJs. After learning and understanding basics of AngularJs I was thinking of a cool project that I can do to make my understanding more robust.
I thought of creating a simple &lt;strong&gt;Social Network&lt;/strong&gt; type application which I could implement in AngularJs.
I decided to go mobile again and was looking for a framework which was using AngularJs at its core to build a Hybrid Mobile Appilication. After searching a bit I came across Ionic Framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ionic-framework&#34;&gt;Ionic Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic is the open source mobile sdk that will allow you to build Progressive Web and Native Apps easily.
Features Of Ionic Framework -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integeration with &lt;strong&gt;cordova&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses &lt;strong&gt;AngularJs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides extensive set of components like list, buttons, label, header, footer, tab-navigation etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Command Line Interface for debugging and building application(I used iOS and android)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports SaSS and Less for themeing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-comparison-with-react-native-and-ionic&#34;&gt;Quick Comparison with React-Native and Ionic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;react-native&#34;&gt;React-Native&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-app-million-words&#34;&gt;The App - Million Words.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the concept of &lt;strong&gt;Sex of Ideas&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/matt_ridley_when_ideas_have_sex&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s the ted talk &lt;/a&gt;where in you take mate two ideas and derive a new idea out of it.
So here the &lt;strong&gt;Million Words&lt;/strong&gt; app was the child of &lt;strong&gt;Quora&lt;/strong&gt;(where you ask questions) and &lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;(where you post pictures with some description).
Yes, you guessed it right in Million Words you can ask questions that can be only answered using pictures and short description.
And the name million words because &lt;strong&gt;A picture is worth million words&lt;/strong&gt;
Following were the features I implemented in the first version of Million words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi User&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can add profile pictures and update their info(name, email, short description)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other users can view profiles(Info, question, answers) of the users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Question&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user can ask question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upvote and downvote a question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate Screen for unanswered questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer to a Question&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can answer the question by uploading a picture(from gallery or camera) along with short description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can comment on any answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can like the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can view other user&amp;rsquo;s answer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;libraries-and-technologies-used&#34;&gt;Libraries and Technologies Used -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ionic Framework v1&lt;/strong&gt; - To build the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cordova Library&lt;/strong&gt; - Bridge between the native and Web comes with basic native functionality like logging, toast etc. I added Dialog and Camera plugin too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grunt&lt;/strong&gt; - To build and run tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NPM&lt;/strong&gt; - To add and update ionic and cordova plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bower&lt;/strong&gt; - To add libraries for the app like moments, firebase etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firebase&lt;/strong&gt; - Google&amp;rsquo;s Awesome Realtime database which was backend of my application. I used Authentication and Database of the Firebase more about firebase here &amp;ndash; &amp;ndash;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; - I learned git a lot in this project becuase I made myself use branching for a feature. So it was fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geny Motion&lt;/strong&gt; - Best Android Emulator I came across. I am mentioning this because it was a big relief for me when I came across Geny Motion, it&amp;rsquo;s fast and simple to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>