<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 08:41:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gift Parents can Give to their Children</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2016/12/08/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 08:41:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2016/12/08/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; - I am no parenting expert, just putting out my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--People are generally not experienced in parenting, but they get over time. And parenting according me is the most difficult and 
challenging task. One of the reason why I think parenting is difficult because it involves shaping a character of individual who
will go out in the society and it is safe to say that Osama Bin Laden and Bill Gates are ouput of parenting. 
So parenting is like passing on your learnings about the world to your offsprings. I feel this task involves great amount of responsibility.

I was lucky to have great Parents, despite having poor schooling experience because we lived in very remote Indian village having no English Medium School in the radius of 20kms I flourished very well.
The reason why I consider my parents to be great because they __trusted me__, what I mean by that is I had full ownership of my life and my parents were always there behind my back.
This allowed me to take lots of bad decisions and learned from them and I feel totally responsible for what I am right now.
The decisions can be minor or major like which school I will go to, should I opt engineering or medical or something else, should I go to kota.
I am not implying that my parents let me suffer by my bad decisions, no that is not the case, they knew when situations were going in the wrong directions and took control immediately.

Giving fi--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parenting is hard and for majority of parents its is their first time. So we all know what it is like to do an
difficult task with inexperience. Apart from cleaning shit and pee stuff the part where it really gets difficult is when
you are supposed to part your values to your offsprings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think when you have kids there is kind of Power you get. Power of releasing a product in the society who might become a president or might be a criminal.
&lt;strong&gt;So with great power comes great responsiblity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to have great parents. Now that I am an adult and kind of on my own when I look back and realized what were the key great things that every parent should consider. While I am not saying I am very successful individual but I think
my parents were very successful parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there might be great researches out there which might make this post obvious and noob these are my thoughts and what I learned from my parents. I want to point out some great parenting
style that my parents adopted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating an Environment of Free Will&lt;/strong&gt;- What I mean by that is as a kid we barely make decisions partly because we are too dumb at that time and also our parents are sometimes too protective but I think allowing me to make many crucial decisions of my life with their support was the best thing my parents did to me. It has made me more responsible and less-blaming-on-others human being which I think is great skill to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encouraging Honesty&lt;/strong&gt; - I know it is difficult to explain to a 10-year old what is honesty. But I think the reason kids lie most is because parents scare the shit out of them for small mistakes, which causes the child to lie. I think instead of scolding a child about his/her mistakes parents should try to make sure that he/she admits mistake and learn from them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Comparing with Sharmaji&amp;rsquo;s Child&lt;/strong&gt; - I hate when any parent compares his/her child with other child. I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand how comparing will ever help in your child&amp;rsquo;s development. Please provide some actionable and constructive feedbacks if you want your child&amp;rsquo;s development and understand that every child is unique(&lt;strong&gt;Yes for the millionth time!&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Putting in Hostel before Secondary Education&lt;/strong&gt; - I can&amp;rsquo;t thank my parents enough for letting me stay with them till my 10th(After that I had no choice) despite living in village. How will you ever impart your knowledge and values if you put your son/daughter in a hostel at such an early stage? Its like putting a kid in a factory(Sorry but True). You have kids because you want to leave a legacy behind you and putting them in hostels never helps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Believing and Trusting Kids&lt;/strong&gt; - I think a parent should be confident that his/her offspring is capable of doing things own its own and not worrying and being paranoid about them all the time is very important for a healthy parent-child relationship.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending Time With Kids&lt;/strong&gt; - I was lucky to born in prosperous and business family. And we always had time for &lt;strong&gt;vacations&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;daily-fun-family-time&lt;/strong&gt;(like playing sports, watching movie together etc etc). I have good amount of fun memories with parents which I am really happy about and cherish those moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom to Try&lt;/strong&gt; - My parents bought Computer when I was 10 year old doofus and having computer at that time was kinda of a big thing. It is safe to say I was introduced with &lt;strong&gt;love of my life&lt;/strong&gt;. But at the same I attended karate classes, music classes and many other classes but ended up with marrying computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-sure-there-are-many-other-great-things-that-my-parents-did-which-made-me-a-better-person-and-i-will-surely-update-them-if-i-could-recall-them-please-share-your-thoughts-and-views-on-the-same&#34;&gt;I am sure there are many other great things that my parents did which made me a better person and I will surely update them if I could recall them, please share your thoughts and views on the same.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;till-then&#34;&gt;Till then ✌🏻&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/blogs/termial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 10:41:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/blogs/termial/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer-This post is not for windows user&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;unlocking-potential-of-terminal-one-command-at-a-time&#34;&gt;Unlocking Potential of Terminal One Command at a Time.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a pro user of terminal, but recently I started working on technologies which forced me to use &lt;strong&gt;CLI(Command Line Interface)&lt;/strong&gt;
for tasks like building source, running server, deploying the code etc.
Generally when you use GUI while you figure out a workflow which is most optimized for you this might include
knowing all the keyboard shortcuts, optimizing the Editor&amp;rsquo;s layout according to you, creating shortcuts on your Desktop and many more which I cannot think of right now.
But when you are working on terminal your choices are limited by how you use commands provided and remembering them is a daunting task.
As a programmer I feel the power of making my computer work the way I want, so I had to figure out a way to make Terminal work for me to make my workflow optimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aliasing&#34;&gt;Aliasing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Word &lt;strong&gt;Alias&lt;/strong&gt; has many meanings if you will google it but the one that suits here is &lt;em&gt;an alternate name for someone or something&lt;/em&gt;.
In terminal also we can pretty much alias anything we want, meaning we can rename any complicated command in our own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How this is helpful?-You may ask&lt;/strong&gt;
Let me show you how  -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say everytime I want to work on my personal website I have to write following commands in the terminal -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$cd ~/Documents/myProjects/myWebsite&lt;/code&gt; to change my working directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$code .&lt;/code&gt; - To open &lt;strong&gt;VS Code&lt;/strong&gt; (Editor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$hugo serve&lt;/code&gt; - To start my local server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After Aliasing&lt;/strong&gt;
I just write &lt;code&gt;$mySite_run&lt;/code&gt;. This single commands executes all three commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enough jibber-jabber show me how to do it&lt;/strong&gt;
Look for ~/.bash_profile, ~/.bash_login or  ~/.profile which are files which are executed whenever you open the terminal, we will add our alias command
here so that we can use them whenever terminal starts.
If you weren&amp;rsquo;t able to find any of the aboove mentioned files type &lt;code&gt;touch ~/.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; to create new file.
Once the file is created you can open it any editor of your choice and start editing it.
For the example that I gave above alias command will look like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias mySite_run=&#39;cd ~/Documents/mySite/; code .;hugo server&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;;&lt;/code&gt; in command helps to execute more than one commands in one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other alias that I use are following -
- &lt;code&gt;alias poweroff=&#39;sudo /sbin/shutdown -h now&#39;&lt;/code&gt; - for force mac shutdown
- &lt;code&gt;alias mysql=&#39;/usr/local/mysql-5.5.25-osx10.6-x86_64/bin/mysql -u root&#39;&lt;/code&gt; - to start mysql installation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add as many aliases you want and optimize your daily workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One quick pro tip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and keep forgetting stuff I like to print my alias whenever I open my terminal using &lt;code&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt;
so lets I write&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo -e &#39;Use\nmySite_run-to edit website\namazon_project-to edit amazon_project&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which will give me output like this whenever I open the terminal which helps me keep track of my aliases
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/img/terminal/terminal_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Terminal Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go Ahead Geek Out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me know if you have more cool terminal tricks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ionic million words</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/ionic-million-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 12:53:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/ionic-million-words/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Native App To Manage Expense</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/react-native-money-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 09:30:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/react-native-money-management/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;framework-react-native&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framework React-Native&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created this app when I started learning Javascript and explored different frameworks in Javascript, then I bumped into react-native and was really amazed
by facebook&amp;rsquo;s approach of creating HYBRID Mobile App. React-Native is build around the philosophy that &lt;strong&gt;learn once and write everywhere&lt;/strong&gt; over &lt;strong&gt;write once and run everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;(philosophy of phonegap).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have to write more uncommon code for Android and iOS in React-Native but you will be writing in same language(i.e. JS) and everything will be rendered natively when you will run the app.
I was at that time working on an Android Application and thought of writing a simple app on this platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some useful resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also get started on react-native by following &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/getting-started.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazing list of react-native plugins &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/react/wiki/Complementary-Tools&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For layouts react-native heavily uses flexbox, handy reference &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/a-guide-to-flexbox/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;app-money-management&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App&lt;/strong&gt; Money Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jitenagarwal19/money_new1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;So the reasons why I built this app are&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to learn react-native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to build a simple app to track my expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the need to create my own expense management app because all the expense management apps out there are complex and do many things, which i didnt want.
So I figured out building a very simple app that will do the job.
So my basic requirements were very simple -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have some fields to enter my expenses - (Name of expense, expense, and some description)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have categories to store my expenses(Food, Travel, Shopping, Home and Other)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Way to view the expenses on the basis of categories and time(monthly or yearly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store the expenses locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Improvements that I will implement in the future&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding OCR to scan bill images directly in the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storing data in the cloud (like firebase)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing User login and rollout public version of the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-i-came-up-the-following-ui-which-i-find-very-useful-and-easy-to-use&#34;&gt;So I came up the following UI which I find very useful and easy to use -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am using &lt;a href=&#34;https://material.google.com/style/color.html#&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Material Design Color Palette&lt;/a&gt;, in case you are curious how I came up with these colors
&lt;strong&gt;Home View with Transactions View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/img/money/home1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Home View 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home View with Category View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/img/money/home2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Home View 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearly View&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/img/money/yearly.png&#34; alt=&#34;Yearly View&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading-please-feel-free-to-fork-this-project-or-to-provide-any-feedbacks&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading please feel free to fork this project or to provide any feedbacks.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist Data</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/persist-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 12:09:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/persist-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a simple expense management application for myself in react-native(  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jitenagarwal.com/projects/react-native-money-management/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expense Management App&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ). For this app I needed a functionality where I could use localstorage and store the entries in the key/value form.
Then I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/asyncstorage.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; feature in react-native and build this simple app. Which includes two fields key and value and list to show the stored values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/1337Pa1QJ1CIve.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Persist Data&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-https-github-com-jitenagarwal19-persistdata-is-the-github-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jitenagarwal19/PersistData&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the github link&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-https-youtu-be-kr8230voewm-is-the-short-youtube-video-demoing-the-app&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Kr8230voEWM&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the short youtube video demoing the app.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading-please-feel-free-to-fork-this-project-or-to-provide-any-feedbacks&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading please feel free to fork this project or to provide any feedbacks.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rect Native App - Weather</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/weather-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 11:43:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/projects/weather-app/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is very basic app that I implemented when I was learning react-native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.giphy.com/Q93Z84MUc7NUA.gif&#34; alt=&#34;GIF&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can move the pin anywhere in the map to get the weather data of that region. Coordinates of the pin will used to fetch the weather data using this &lt;a href=&#34;https://openweathermap.org/api&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;open weahter api&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
Things I learn while implementing this project -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map React-Native bridge(Only available for iOS at that time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promises in Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved understanding of states in React Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Custom Component in React-Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-https-github-com-jitenagarwal19-weather-app-is-the-github-link&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jitenagarwal19/Weather-app&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the github link&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-scvs7a2ymkk-is-the-short-youtube-video-demoing-the-app&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=scVS7A2Ymkk&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the short youtube video demoing the app.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks-for-reading-please-feel-free-to-fork-this-project-or-to-provide-any-feedbacks&#34;&gt;Thanks for reading please feel free to fork this project or to provide any feedbacks.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>