<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 21:52:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/2019-year-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 21:52:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/2019-year-review/</guid>
      <description>2019 was easily the best year of my life so far. No, I didn’t start a company. No, I didn’t get married. No, I didn’t get a Job in Apple. But I still think 2019 was full of amazing learnings, travel stories, friendships.
When I was thinking of what format this blog should be in. The first idea that came to my mind was to just write down the most interesting events month-wise, but then I thought that would be too boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Vipassana Experience - Kathmandu, Nepal</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-vipassana-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 15:24:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-vipassana-experience/</guid>
      <description>It was 26th march 2018 around 11 am I was resting in zostel Kathmandu&amp;rsquo;s terrace. I was recollecting my thoughts on what has happened to me for the past 11 days. My mind was uncomfortably quiet, I was trying to distract it by various thoughts but again it would settle to my body sensations, I could hear the tiniest sound my body was making. It was feeling awkward to be back in the real world — a world full of noises, distractions, hate, and love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I gained from 2 10-days retreat (Vipassana)</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/vipassana-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:47:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/vipassana-benefits/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about Vipassana and want to up your meditation game. You should check it out (Official website)
It is a meditation technique originated in India and was rediscovered by Lord Buddha. You learn how to maintain a balanced and calm mind by observing your bodily sensations.
Vipassana so to speak is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea. It&amp;rsquo;s quite intense and not one of those fantasized meditation retreat camps where everyone seems to be in zen mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Do This After Coming Back From Vipassana</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/you-should-do-this-after-coming-back-from-vipassana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/you-should-do-this-after-coming-back-from-vipassana/</guid>
      <description>So, you have completed the arduous 10-day Vipassana course and now you are all set to bear fruits of Vipassana in real life. But you know it, you can only benefit from the Vipassana practice if you consciously and continuously plug Vipassana in your everyday life. It would be unwise to assume that you will benefit from Vipassana by just completing the 10-day course and not following up on the practice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>