<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye 2016</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/bye-bye-2016</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:57:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/bye-bye-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 1st January 2016 I am waking up little late than my usual time and I certainly miss the sun rise(DAMN!). Trying to do some reflection and thinking should I be happy about my previous year or should I be excited about the opportunities 2017 will bring. 2016 was quite eventful for me I lived this year more lively and consciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While trying to remember my events from 2016 tears(yes I am man and I cry sometimes) are trickling down from my eyes may be there is something more I could have done maybe its the place where I am working now is
not the right one for me and I expected myself to move out from here but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Maybe in 2016 my startup should have took off but didn&amp;rsquo;t. I am looking in the mirror(also typing this blog at the same time) and trying not
to get gloomy about things that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to achieve but I should be happy about the things that I learned and be grateful about another happy year of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real question that I should be asking myself is are you a better version of yourself from what you were last year -
And the answer comes yes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am obviuosly a much better person than I was when 2016 started, I was rude, arrogant, fat, not doing much learning, not travelling much, not talking to people much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took bad decisions which led me to failures that will always happen every year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Every year there will be - 
    New sets of failures,
    New sets of success, 
    Bad decisions,
    People that I might loose contact from,
    Happy moments which I wished would have never ended,
    Events I wished would never have crossed paths with,
    Learnings that will remain engraved with me for the rest of my life,
    Sights that my eyes will see and I will never forget, 
    Words that came out of my mouth that would make or break someone’s heart. 

Every year I will be growing....
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I can remember some of the things I learned in 2016 and I will keep working on them and learn new things -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to optimize my schedule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to concentrate on something&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to learn new frameworks and use them quickly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Different kinds of philosophy and I am yet to decide which one I will go with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git to the full usage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get something done using the official doc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to choose myself always&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the principles that drive me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivates me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I can always keep growing and learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to live more carefree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to give a fuck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to deal with difficult people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to keep calm in difficult situations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to fall in love with pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to embrace failures(really?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to let go things and people and subsidize my feelings which are strong but are not good for my future and career&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to control my instant gratification monkey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to procrastinate and get things done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to live a fit lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to travel in Style.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saying No.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to expect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to compare myself from others&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a beautiful event sunrise is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey There! Two Thousand Seventeen</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/hey-there-two-thousand-seventeen</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:14:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/hey-there-two-thousand-seventeen</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt; is here and lots of great things are about to happen this year in my life and in the world. I will be shifting to a &lt;strong&gt;new place&lt;/strong&gt;, I will turn &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;, I will be completing &lt;strong&gt;2 years of my professional career&lt;/strong&gt; and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 was a great year for me it raised the bars high for 2017 and I am hoping this will be the trend for the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year my main focus will be to an amazing programmer, I still am a decent programmer and I tried different learning techniques and methods in 2016, this year I am hoping to take it off the charts, I am yet to create list of actionable items that will take me to the fulfillment of this goal. Another thing that has caught my interest in 2016 was reading books, I can’t express in words what benefits I have gained from reading books. My area of interest in book reading will be more in philosophy and economics and fiction while I am traveling or when I want to sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also here are few objectives that I will achieve in 2017 and this list will expand for at least 3 months (order is irrelevant)-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-weekend-fasting&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Weekend Fasting&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the few things that changed my life in 2016 was becoming fit and active, I think I was in my &lt;strong&gt;fittest version&lt;/strong&gt; in 2016. This year I want to take it to a next level and start implementing no carbs weekend, I am hoping to start this small like 1 weekend in one month, then twice and so on. Benefits of this -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal Cleansing of body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During weekends I generally stay at home doing my things, which sometimes leads to the unwanted stuffing of calories, this &lt;strong&gt;discipline&lt;/strong&gt; will put a check on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will compliment in my adverse time.(&lt;strong&gt;You don’t need unhealthy food to rejuvenate or uplift your mood&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will make me more tolerant to pain and hunger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-cross-borders-of-india&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Cross Borders of India&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah!! 2016 was full of traveling &lt;strong&gt;Leh&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kerala&lt;/strong&gt;, so many treks and I really enjoyed all of the trips. My bonding with friends, family and myself increased after these trips and I have so many &lt;strong&gt;happy memories to cherish&lt;/strong&gt;. I want to take this traveling spirit at a next step and put my foot out of India. It’s not like I hate India, I love it but taking an international trip was on my checklist for a long time and I intend to check it off this year. Following are the destinations in my head, please suggest more in comments
* Dubai
* Hong Kong
* Jordan
* Thailand or Bangkok :p
* Maybe some parts of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-a-month-without-whatsapp-leaving-all-the-groups&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;A Month Without Whatsapp &amp;amp; Leaving all the Groups&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t hate WhatsApp, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome feat of engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, but sometimes it makes me wonder how much time I and people surrounding me waste on WhatsApp. I ditched facebook in 2016 and my life is pretty much unaffected I am hoping WhatsApp is overrated too and I can easily get rid of it. &lt;strong&gt;It just surrounding pressure that forces you to use Whatsapp&lt;/strong&gt;, I am not able to get rid of the WhatsApp now because I live in a no network zone and WhatsApp is an alternative for calling and communicating. Once I move out of this zone I will definitely ditch Whatsapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-active-blogging&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Active blogging&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always &lt;strong&gt;bad at communicating my ideas to the world&lt;/strong&gt; because I feel that my linguistic part of the brain is weak and I need to make it stronger. &lt;strong&gt;Active blogging will allow me to force my ideas and thoughts out of my head and put it in words&lt;/strong&gt;. What I am planning to do is put out &lt;strong&gt;at least two blogs per week&lt;/strong&gt; (long or short doesn’t matter) and during my free space of time, I will keep thinking of a good idea or topic for the blog which I will note it down. Blogging so far feels great it’s like open sourcing your thoughts to the world, at this point in time, I know that very few people read my blogs and I will try to increase my audience too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-progressive-web-app-of-my-website&#34;&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Progressive Web App of My Website&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put out &lt;a href=&#34;jitenagarwal.com&#34;&gt;jitenagarwal.com&lt;/a&gt; during fall of 2016, and it started with the idea of getting a &lt;strong&gt;better job&lt;/strong&gt; and as a &lt;strong&gt;medium to showcase my work&lt;/strong&gt;, but now I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stop here. More I think about how I can use my website more Ideas pop in my mind and more effort that will require. Right now this website is just static(which was a good start). But I am hoping to move out of that and make it like an application and implement following things -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo sharing Page(Instagram is for Millennials and Muggles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track my habits and create charts of trends using D3.js (see point 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging the places(restaurants, hotels any other tourist site) I have been&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing technical and project experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing all other stuff (books, podcasts, movies, things that I have bought)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-scheduling&#34;&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took &lt;strong&gt;good control of my time&lt;/strong&gt; in 2016 as compared to my previous years but when I listen to awesome people on the planet talking about how much valuable time is and it makes me feel like a jerk, throwing my time here and there. Basically, I am planning, Scheduling on Weekly and Monthly basis which will allow me to manage my time resource wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-logging-everything-and-taking-notes&#34;&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Logging Everything and Taking Notes&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;strong&gt;workout intensely&lt;/strong&gt; you understand the power of logs. Without logging your workout, everything goes for a toss and you cannot &lt;strong&gt;track your progress and areas of improvement&lt;/strong&gt;. And &lt;strong&gt;things which cannot be measured cannot be improved&lt;/strong&gt;. So, I thought why not apply the logging framework for everything in my life I am working on &lt;strong&gt;creating an application&lt;/strong&gt; for it and I will track following things on it -
* Workout logs (obviously)
* Programming languages I worked on every day
* My Diet habits(avoiding sugar, fried and other Junk)
* Reading Habit
* And Other habits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-stop-giving-free-advice&#34;&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Stop giving Free Advice&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave lots of free advice to people in 2016 only with good intentions and to help them in any way I can. But giving free advice kind of sets a &lt;strong&gt;tiny bit of expectations&lt;/strong&gt; in my head of them following my advice and you know how dangerous is expecting from other people(&lt;strong&gt;MOSTLY DISAPPOINTMENT&lt;/strong&gt;). So to save myself from Disappointment I will just put out my thoughts and help on my blog and will &lt;strong&gt;stop giving free advice&lt;/strong&gt; unless anyone asks for it. Quote from Joker comes to my mind which fits perfectly here - &lt;strong&gt;IF YOU ARE GOOD AT SOMETHING NEVER DO IT FOR FREE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-5-minutes-gratitude-journal&#34;&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;5 Minutes gratitude journal&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored a lot of ways of journaling which will fit my lifestyle and I have finally settled on this technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-follow-stoicism-religiously&#34;&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Follow Stoicism Religiously&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dont know what Stoicism here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Stoicism&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I have come to understanding that life is going to be &lt;strong&gt;tough &amp;amp; painful&lt;/strong&gt;. Subsidising these painful moments and hardships by partying and doing other muggle thing is really not my style. I was looking for a certain philosophy to deal with pain and hardships which lead me to &lt;strong&gt;Stoicism&lt;/strong&gt;. I am currently reading all the literature and books around Stoicism to figure out how to adopt a Stoic Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not my exhaustive list of resolutions but I will keep updating also I am asking my friends and family about one resolution that they would like to add on my list, which will make me reflect more on myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any thoughts and comments to share please share them I would love to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-hope-you-too-have-an-amazing-2017&#34;&gt;I HOPE YOU TOO HAVE AN AMAZING 2017.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peace&#34;&gt;PEACE.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>