<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 22:12:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Perception Matters</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/03/31/why-perception-matters</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 22:12:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/03/31/why-perception-matters</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-perception&#34;&gt;What is Perception?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perception is how we understand things after knowing about the situation/incident/event.
Perception is basically the output of your thought process after analyzing the input which here is information about any event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say event it can be any event -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person cutting you off in the traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Osama bin laden killing people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone having a baby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You getting a promotion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, anything which increases the entropy of universe can be called an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, information about the event is same, but why do different people have different perception about that event?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/img/perception/illustration.png&#34; alt=&#34;Perception Illustration&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-perception&#34;&gt;Why Perception?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reason why I want to talk about perception is because it plays an important role in our life and we tend to almost ignore it. We ignore the fact that the way we perceive things might not be the way things are. Our beliefs, culture and many other biases come in the way when looking at an event and try to understand it. Wrong perceiving of the event might sometimes lead to negative emotions.
I got into thinking that how can I change my &lt;strong&gt;lens(Perception thought process)&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid generally all negative emotions which might make me sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-am-talking-about-this-kind-of-changes&#34;&gt;I am talking about this kind of changes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident 1&lt;/strong&gt; - A person cuts you off in the traffic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception 1&lt;/strong&gt; - That $%#$%$%#$%! don’t know how to drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception 2&lt;/strong&gt; - (S)he must be in an emergency situation and may have to reach somewhere quickly. I have no reason to be angry here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident 2&lt;/strong&gt; - An uber cab driver behaves rudely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception 1&lt;/strong&gt; - It was my bad day that I landed in this Uber, I will definitely rate this guy 1 star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perception 2&lt;/strong&gt; - Sitting and Driving all day is a boring and frustrating Job, I should be thankful to him for doing this job and taking the pain. Little blabbering can be ignored given that pain that person is going through daily (I am not saying every driver hates their job, just trying to make a point here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see generally you always &lt;strong&gt;have a choice&lt;/strong&gt; whether to get affected by that incident or let it pass. I know this is a tough thing to do when things don’t work your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;positive-perception-better-life&#34;&gt;Positive Perception = Better Life&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am doing this &lt;strong&gt;conscious effort&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure I have a positive perception of events in life. Also, please note here I am not talking about letting people pass when they cheat or betray you that, just incidents which doesn’t affect you much like mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I always keep these in mind which is very helpful in having a positive perception about things-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost every stranger, co-worker, friend, acquaintance, fling, customer service representative, driver, waiter, customer, client, neighbor, and person on the internet you come across:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has a family who loves them and vice versa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has hopes and dreams and regrets and frustrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has as many thoughts going through their head at all times as you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is dealing with random health problems, trying to make ends meet financially, and is probably tired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might be supporting one or more other human beings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might be just a little sad all the time about a tragedy in their past&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Might be the most important person in someone else’s life&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is just trying to figure out how to be happy
i.e. They’re a full human just like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remembering-that-will-make-you-kinder-and-more-empathetic&#34;&gt;Remembering that will make you kinder and more empathetic.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agree-disagree-have-something-to-add&#34;&gt;Agree? Disagree? Have something to add?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Survived Despite Being Stupid</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/03/24/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 21:23:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/03/24/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Few days back I indulged myself in teaching basic mathematics to a 10-year old kid. While teaching him I realised that how quickly he was grasping stuff compared to how difficult that was for me. This incident let me to realize that I was always a dumb kid, it always took me time to figure out stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am not at peak of my career, but reaching where I am now for dumb kid like me I think is a wonder.
So, I would like to share how I survived in this extremely competitive world despite being dumb-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistence&lt;/strong&gt; - This is the No. 1 reason of my survival I guess, while I know being persistent is not easy. But if you know that you are dumb and you have to work hard to get things done then Persistence is the key to get things done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowing you are Dumb&lt;/strong&gt; - You can only work on your weakness, if you have identified one. I think you have to be humble about your knowings and weakness. I know that I don&amp;rsquo;t know shit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being Ugly and Fat&lt;/strong&gt; - I am thankful to god(or whoever) for making me ugly and fat. Everyone knows, things are relatively difficult for ugly and fat(unless you are in stone age) - you dont make good first impression, you are lazy, you have low-confidence etc,etc. I have to fight harder for everything, and this hard-working nature becomes hardwired when you have to do it so often. It makes you a emotionally stronger person and more failure accepting in nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeking Help&lt;/strong&gt; - One thing I have always kept in mind is I cannot survive without taking help from people no matter where I am.(Specialization is the key to humankind). I also know that there are always smart people in the world from whom I can seek help and grow. I am almost never hesitant to ask for help and this has made me a smarter person. ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dxNQebY-Qdw&#34;&gt;What Steve Jobs has to say on seeking help&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become Gandhi when you look at Mirror&lt;/strong&gt; - I have never lied to myself when I look at mirror. When I stand in front of mirror, I ask tough questions and be honest about those questions. Questions I asked to myself -

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you working hard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you doing what you are supposed to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you should never be embarrassed in front of mirror. &lt;strong&gt;GO NAKED&lt;/strong&gt;(maybe literally ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning&lt;/strong&gt; - I have completed my formal studies 2 years back and every single day since then I have learned something new. I have very child like curiosity and with power of internet in your hands no question should go unanswered in my opinion. Like the other day I learned the full-form of Wifi and story behind that name(I can bet most of you dont know).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Zero Days&lt;/strong&gt; - I will recommend you read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/getdisciplined/comments/1q96b5/i_just_dont_care_about_myself/cdah4af/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. Magic will happen in your life if you start following this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-am-doing-currently-to-make-my-life-better&#34;&gt;What I am doing Currently to make my Life Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following Stoicism - I need a philosophy for life. Read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://ryanholiday.net/stoicism-a-practical-philosophy-you-can-actually-use/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disciplined Life - Everything and everyday goes according to schedule. Time for Clićhe - If you don&amp;rsquo;t run the day, day runs you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;intermittent Fasting - On Tuesdays and Fridays, I eat no carbs and have one meal in 24 hours. Read benefits &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.health.com/nutrition/intermittent-fasting-diet&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Books - One of the reason I am dumb because I didn&amp;rsquo;t make them my best friends, making them now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;followup-readings&#34;&gt;FollowUp Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/2015/11/the-cook-and-the-chef-musks-secret-sauce.html&#34;&gt;Tim Urban&amp;rsquo;s Idea to improve your life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;amp;pid=sites&amp;amp;srcid=ZGVmYXVsdGRvbWFpbnxlYm9va3Nkb3dubG9hZG5vdzIwMTZ8Z3g6MjY3NGU2Njk5N2QxNjViMg&#34;&gt;Principle by Ray Dahlio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-know-you-are-definitely-smarter-than-me-let-me-know-how-you-tackle-with-competitive-world&#34;&gt;I know you are definitely smarter than me, let me know how you tackle with competitive world.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;peace&#34;&gt;Peace.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of People in a Team</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/14/types-of-people-in-a-team</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 20:53:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/14/types-of-people-in-a-team</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;The Office&lt;/strong&gt; and felt it was really stupid, fun but stupid. I really thought it was all fictional and it was there for fun and totally unrelatable to real life. Ohh boy!! I was wrong! I was wrong by an arm’s length. There are types of people who you will find in your workplace that have unique and totally useless qualities. And the funny part is they like to talk about those qualities. I am one of them agreed, in someone else’s head but during one normal day, after completing my routine coding tasks I take off my headphones and looked around. I just couldn’t stop laughing. I thought someone who created “The Office” would have definitely been in this situation and he/she too had a good laugh and enough balls &amp;amp; brain to make a comedy sitcom out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always several sides of a situation, when I am frustrated and don’t have enough control over situation I try to see things through Seinfeld’s perspective and try to make funny situations out of those. It is fun you should totally try it. I really enjoy how different kinds of people come together in an enclosed space and try to do something we call “WORK”. I tried to categorised homo-sapiens in a team after observing few teams. Please take no offence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-people-in-team&#34;&gt;Types of people in team -&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know it all&lt;/strong&gt; - You will always find that guy/girl you just needs to be part of every argument/discussion irrespective of whether (s)he knows about it or not. The confidence that this kind of sapiens show is very unique and admirable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One who always come late&lt;/strong&gt; - It&amp;rsquo;s high time of the day when everyone is done checking their mails and everyone have cracked their knuckles and are deep into work(or trying to be). Quitely that guy will sneak up and will sit on his spot as if he was always there. Also this species have very thick skin, they are unaffected by anything that comes out of manager&amp;rsquo;s mouth regarding their punctuality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One who will quit soon&lt;/strong&gt; - This type of person is generally unsatisfied by his current avenues and complains a lot and in the end never forgets to add &amp;ldquo;Who I am to say, I will be long gone by next month&amp;rdquo;. But unfortunately this human always find a reason of not accepting the &amp;ldquo;offer&amp;rdquo; from another organisation and decides to stay for another month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One who says he does not belong here&lt;/strong&gt; - Similar to 3rd one but this human behaves like zen and talks in some other kind of language. He/she will do whatever show (s)he doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong here. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to spot people like this if you are in a corporate and dressing is priority, he will wear shabby clothes, will be very ungroomed and don’t like to follow company&amp;rsquo;s code of conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i1226.photobucket.com/albums/ee410/irvinc101/tumblr_lntnlaTOAH1qbqrtb.gif&#34; alt=&#34;I dont belong here&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mother of all gossips&lt;/strong&gt; - Everyone is quitely working, you went to a person for a work related query and that was your biggest mistake because that person will now not stop his/her useless &amp;amp; mind-numbing gossip. People like these are like parasites they survive on ears of people around them. They will die if you would stop listening to them and you will die(or your brain cells will) if you will start listening to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/G5qubSIcLmhsQ/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Gossip Girl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Manager&lt;/strong&gt; - Managers have the shittiest job in the entire organisation. He does nothing but passes messages from top to bottom. His employees throw shit at him and his managers throw shit at him. But in the end it&amp;rsquo;s never his fault, it&amp;rsquo;s always someone else&amp;rsquo;s fault. This guy must be living in existential crisis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/yoJC2i270b1mQvcDdK/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Manager&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manager’s Right Arm&lt;/strong&gt; - You always see a guy standing besides your manager laughing at his jokes, everyone hates him in the team. You cannot gossip about manager when he is around. He thinks he is the next manager if the current manager dies, but that day never comes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/lMVNl6XxTvXgs/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Manager&#39;s Right Arm&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One who does not exist&lt;/strong&gt; - That guy in the team sitting in the quite corner of every meeting and event. You don&amp;rsquo;t know his name he doesn&amp;rsquo;t your name or for that matter anyone&amp;rsquo;s name in the team. He is there to get his shit done and go home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superstar of team&lt;/strong&gt; - You know that person in the team who knows everything about your team&amp;rsquo;s project let it be the oldest or newest feature of your application, he/she knows it all. Everyone seeks his/her help for any query and always have a queue lined up of teammates to resolve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://25.media.tumblr.com/7716ef547264521e476a067b1c8d2717/tumblr_mwjlmfJ1vx1rkiuhro1_500.gif&#34; alt=&#34;SuperStar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Young One&lt;/strong&gt; - Intern/Young Grad whatever almost baby like looks very naive in everything. No one gives him/her work, everyone is thankful that atleast he/she showed up for work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/JWZmzj1KNzZBu/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Young&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The one with negative IQ&lt;/strong&gt; - You must have meet this kind of person, as soon as he opens his mouth you are sure his parents must have dropped him when he was a baby and his brain never recovered from that injury. He is the one responsible for lowering team&amp;rsquo;s average IQ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/pFwRzOLfuGHok/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Negative IQ&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alcoholic&lt;/strong&gt; - That pair of heavy eyes yet to recover from last night&amp;rsquo;s hangover. Highly suffering from depression and in his life, alcohol has become problem and solution of all his problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QqbVct5FXj0/U6eZCIvvCYI/AAAAAAAAAQc/EuBn9j7wZsM/s1600/drinking+gif.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Alcholic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One who cannot stop talking about Mangoes at his village.&lt;/strong&gt; - Remember meeting that person who&amp;rsquo;s only achievement was to be born in a village which is famous for so and so fruit. And that person cannot stop talking about that f**king fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One With Kids&lt;/strong&gt; - This kind of people had nothing to do with their life so they reproduced and now they are superbusy and can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about those noisy little creatures. They log everything about their offsprings- first time it(little creature) pooped yellow, first time it said &amp;ldquo;sjfskfjsfjdfd&amp;rdquo;, first time it breathed.Phew!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qnKFsVHm5Lc/VKJDUk4SCKI/AAAAAAAAF0E/Y6uDpb8KTRI/s1600/baby%2Bmeme%2B2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parent&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The One who is happy about his life&lt;/strong&gt; - This person has everything figured out, he/she has a great spouse, everyone loves him/her at work, always a smile on face and what not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/8VrtCswiLDNnO/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Happy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-i-miss-or-can-you-resemble-any-of-those-in-your-daily-lives-let-me-know-in-the-comments&#34;&gt;What did I miss or can you resemble any of those in your daily lives? Let me know in the comments.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye 2016</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/bye-bye-2016</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:57:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/bye-bye-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 1st January 2016 I am waking up little late than my usual time and I certainly miss the sun rise(DAMN!). Trying to do some reflection and thinking should I be happy about my previous year or should I be excited about the opportunities 2017 will bring. 2016 was quite eventful for me I lived this year more lively and consciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While trying to remember my events from 2016 tears(yes I am man and I cry sometimes) are trickling down from my eyes may be there is something more I could have done maybe its the place where I am working now is
not the right one for me and I expected myself to move out from here but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Maybe in 2016 my startup should have took off but didn&amp;rsquo;t. I am looking in the mirror(also typing this blog at the same time) and trying not
to get gloomy about things that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to achieve but I should be happy about the things that I learned and be grateful about another happy year of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real question that I should be asking myself is are you a better version of yourself from what you were last year -
And the answer comes yes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am obviuosly a much better person than I was when 2016 started, I was rude, arrogant, fat, not doing much learning, not travelling much, not talking to people much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took bad decisions which led me to failures that will always happen every year,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Every year there will be - 
    New sets of failures,
    New sets of success, 
    Bad decisions,
    People that I might loose contact from,
    Happy moments which I wished would have never ended,
    Events I wished would never have crossed paths with,
    Learnings that will remain engraved with me for the rest of my life,
    Sights that my eyes will see and I will never forget, 
    Words that came out of my mouth that would make or break someone’s heart. 

Every year I will be growing....
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I can remember some of the things I learned in 2016 and I will keep working on them and learn new things -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to optimize my schedule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to concentrate on something&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to learn new frameworks and use them quickly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Different kinds of philosophy and I am yet to decide which one I will go with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git to the full usage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get something done using the official doc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to choose myself always&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the principles that drive me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What motivates me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I can always keep growing and learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to live more carefree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to give a fuck&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to deal with difficult people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to keep calm in difficult situations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to fall in love with pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to embrace failures(really?)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to let go things and people and subsidize my feelings which are strong but are not good for my future and career&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to control my instant gratification monkey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to procrastinate and get things done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to live a fit lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to travel in Style.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saying No.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to expect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How not to compare myself from others&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What a beautiful event sunrise is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey There! Two Thousand Seventeen</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/hey-there-two-thousand-seventeen</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:14:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2017/01/01/hey-there-two-thousand-seventeen</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt; is here and lots of great things are about to happen this year in my life and in the world. I will be shifting to a &lt;strong&gt;new place&lt;/strong&gt;, I will turn &lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt;, I will be completing &lt;strong&gt;2 years of my professional career&lt;/strong&gt; and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 was a great year for me it raised the bars high for 2017 and I am hoping this will be the trend for the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year my main focus will be to an amazing programmer, I still am a decent programmer and I tried different learning techniques and methods in 2016, this year I am hoping to take it off the charts, I am yet to create list of actionable items that will take me to the fulfillment of this goal. Another thing that has caught my interest in 2016 was reading books, I can’t express in words what benefits I have gained from reading books. My area of interest in book reading will be more in philosophy and economics and fiction while I am traveling or when I want to sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also here are few objectives that I will achieve in 2017 and this list will expand for at least 3 months (order is irrelevant)-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-weekend-fasting&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Weekend Fasting&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the few things that changed my life in 2016 was becoming fit and active, I think I was in my &lt;strong&gt;fittest version&lt;/strong&gt; in 2016. This year I want to take it to a next level and start implementing no carbs weekend, I am hoping to start this small like 1 weekend in one month, then twice and so on. Benefits of this -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal Cleansing of body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During weekends I generally stay at home doing my things, which sometimes leads to the unwanted stuffing of calories, this &lt;strong&gt;discipline&lt;/strong&gt; will put a check on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will compliment in my adverse time.(&lt;strong&gt;You don’t need unhealthy food to rejuvenate or uplift your mood&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will make me more tolerant to pain and hunger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-cross-borders-of-india&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Cross Borders of India&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah!! 2016 was full of traveling &lt;strong&gt;Leh&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kerala&lt;/strong&gt;, so many treks and I really enjoyed all of the trips. My bonding with friends, family and myself increased after these trips and I have so many &lt;strong&gt;happy memories to cherish&lt;/strong&gt;. I want to take this traveling spirit at a next step and put my foot out of India. It’s not like I hate India, I love it but taking an international trip was on my checklist for a long time and I intend to check it off this year. Following are the destinations in my head, please suggest more in comments
* Dubai
* Hong Kong
* Jordan
* Thailand or Bangkok :p
* Maybe some parts of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-a-month-without-whatsapp-leaving-all-the-groups&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;A Month Without Whatsapp &amp;amp; Leaving all the Groups&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t hate WhatsApp, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome feat of engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, but sometimes it makes me wonder how much time I and people surrounding me waste on WhatsApp. I ditched facebook in 2016 and my life is pretty much unaffected I am hoping WhatsApp is overrated too and I can easily get rid of it. &lt;strong&gt;It just surrounding pressure that forces you to use Whatsapp&lt;/strong&gt;, I am not able to get rid of the WhatsApp now because I live in a no network zone and WhatsApp is an alternative for calling and communicating. Once I move out of this zone I will definitely ditch Whatsapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-active-blogging&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Active blogging&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always &lt;strong&gt;bad at communicating my ideas to the world&lt;/strong&gt; because I feel that my linguistic part of the brain is weak and I need to make it stronger. &lt;strong&gt;Active blogging will allow me to force my ideas and thoughts out of my head and put it in words&lt;/strong&gt;. What I am planning to do is put out &lt;strong&gt;at least two blogs per week&lt;/strong&gt; (long or short doesn’t matter) and during my free space of time, I will keep thinking of a good idea or topic for the blog which I will note it down. Blogging so far feels great it’s like open sourcing your thoughts to the world, at this point in time, I know that very few people read my blogs and I will try to increase my audience too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-progressive-web-app-of-my-website&#34;&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Progressive Web App of My Website&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put out &lt;a href=&#34;jitenagarwal.com&#34;&gt;jitenagarwal.com&lt;/a&gt; during fall of 2016, and it started with the idea of getting a &lt;strong&gt;better job&lt;/strong&gt; and as a &lt;strong&gt;medium to showcase my work&lt;/strong&gt;, but now I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stop here. More I think about how I can use my website more Ideas pop in my mind and more effort that will require. Right now this website is just static(which was a good start). But I am hoping to move out of that and make it like an application and implement following things -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo sharing Page(Instagram is for Millennials and Muggles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track my habits and create charts of trends using D3.js (see point 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging the places(restaurants, hotels any other tourist site) I have been&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing technical and project experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing all other stuff (books, podcasts, movies, things that I have bought)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-scheduling&#34;&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Scheduling&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took &lt;strong&gt;good control of my time&lt;/strong&gt; in 2016 as compared to my previous years but when I listen to awesome people on the planet talking about how much valuable time is and it makes me feel like a jerk, throwing my time here and there. Basically, I am planning, Scheduling on Weekly and Monthly basis which will allow me to manage my time resource wisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-logging-everything-and-taking-notes&#34;&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Logging Everything and Taking Notes&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;strong&gt;workout intensely&lt;/strong&gt; you understand the power of logs. Without logging your workout, everything goes for a toss and you cannot &lt;strong&gt;track your progress and areas of improvement&lt;/strong&gt;. And &lt;strong&gt;things which cannot be measured cannot be improved&lt;/strong&gt;. So, I thought why not apply the logging framework for everything in my life I am working on &lt;strong&gt;creating an application&lt;/strong&gt; for it and I will track following things on it -
* Workout logs (obviously)
* Programming languages I worked on every day
* My Diet habits(avoiding sugar, fried and other Junk)
* Reading Habit
* And Other habits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-stop-giving-free-advice&#34;&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Stop giving Free Advice&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave lots of free advice to people in 2016 only with good intentions and to help them in any way I can. But giving free advice kind of sets a &lt;strong&gt;tiny bit of expectations&lt;/strong&gt; in my head of them following my advice and you know how dangerous is expecting from other people(&lt;strong&gt;MOSTLY DISAPPOINTMENT&lt;/strong&gt;). So to save myself from Disappointment I will just put out my thoughts and help on my blog and will &lt;strong&gt;stop giving free advice&lt;/strong&gt; unless anyone asks for it. Quote from Joker comes to my mind which fits perfectly here - &lt;strong&gt;IF YOU ARE GOOD AT SOMETHING NEVER DO IT FOR FREE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-5-minutes-gratitude-journal&#34;&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;5 Minutes gratitude journal&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored a lot of ways of journaling which will fit my lifestyle and I have finally settled on this technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-follow-stoicism-religiously&#34;&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Follow Stoicism Religiously&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you dont know what Stoicism here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Stoicism&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I have come to understanding that life is going to be &lt;strong&gt;tough &amp;amp; painful&lt;/strong&gt;. Subsidising these painful moments and hardships by partying and doing other muggle thing is really not my style. I was looking for a certain philosophy to deal with pain and hardships which lead me to &lt;strong&gt;Stoicism&lt;/strong&gt;. I am currently reading all the literature and books around Stoicism to figure out how to adopt a Stoic Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not my exhaustive list of resolutions but I will keep updating also I am asking my friends and family about one resolution that they would like to add on my list, which will make me reflect more on myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any thoughts and comments to share please share them I would love to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-hope-you-too-have-an-amazing-2017&#34;&gt;I HOPE YOU TOO HAVE AN AMAZING 2017.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peace&#34;&gt;PEACE.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gift Parents can Give to their Children</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2016/12/08/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 08:41:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal19.github.io/2016/12/08/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt; - I am no parenting expert, just putting out my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--People are generally not experienced in parenting, but they get over time. And parenting according me is the most difficult and 
challenging task. One of the reason why I think parenting is difficult because it involves shaping a character of individual who
will go out in the society and it is safe to say that Osama Bin Laden and Bill Gates are ouput of parenting. 
So parenting is like passing on your learnings about the world to your offsprings. I feel this task involves great amount of responsibility.

I was lucky to have great Parents, despite having poor schooling experience because we lived in very remote Indian village having no English Medium School in the radius of 20kms I flourished very well.
The reason why I consider my parents to be great because they __trusted me__, what I mean by that is I had full ownership of my life and my parents were always there behind my back.
This allowed me to take lots of bad decisions and learned from them and I feel totally responsible for what I am right now.
The decisions can be minor or major like which school I will go to, should I opt engineering or medical or something else, should I go to kota.
I am not implying that my parents let me suffer by my bad decisions, no that is not the case, they knew when situations were going in the wrong directions and took control immediately.

Giving fi--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parenting is hard and for majority of parents it is their first time. So we all know what it is like to do a
difficult task with inexperience. Apart from cleaning shit and pee stuff, the part where it really gets difficult is when
you are supposed to impart your values to your offspring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think when you have kids you get some kind of &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Power&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; you get. Power of releasing a product in the society who might become president or a criminal one day.
&lt;strong&gt;So with great power comes great responsiblity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to have great parents. Now that I am an adult and kind of on my own when I looked back I realized what were the key great things that every parent should consider. While I am not saying I am very successful individual but I think
my parents were very successful parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know there might be great researches out there which might make this post obvious and noob, these are my thoughts and what I learned from my parents. I want to point out some great parenting
style that my parents adopted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating an Environment of Free Will&lt;/strong&gt;- What I mean by that is as a kid we barely make decisions, partly because we are too naive at that time and also our parents are sometimes too protective but I think allowing me to make many crucial decisions of my life with their support was the best thing my parents did to me. It has made me more responsible and less-blaming-others human being which I think is great skill to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encouraging Honesty&lt;/strong&gt; - I know it is difficult to explain to a 10-year old what is honesty. But I think the reason kids lie most is because parents scare the shit out of them for small mistakes, which causes the child to lie. I think instead of scolding a child about his/her mistakes parents should try to make sure that he/she admits mistake and learns from them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Comparing with Sharmaji&amp;rsquo;s Child&lt;/strong&gt; - I hate when any parent compares his/her child with other child(ren). I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand how comparing will ever help in your child&amp;rsquo;s development. Please provide some actionable and constructive feedback if you want your child&amp;rsquo;s development and understand that every child is unique(&lt;strong&gt;Yes for the millionth time!&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not Putting in Hostel before Secondary Education&lt;/strong&gt; - I can&amp;rsquo;t thank my parents enough for letting me stay with them till my 10th(After that I had no choice) despite living in a village. How will you ever impart your knowledge and values if you put your son/daughter in a hostel at such an early stage? Its like putting a kid in a factory(Sorry but True). You have kids because you want to leave a legacy behind you and putting them in hostels never help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Believing and Trusting Kids&lt;/strong&gt; - I think parents should be confident that thier offsprings are capable of doing things own their own and not worrying &amp;amp; being paranoid about them all the time.It is very important for a healthy &lt;strong&gt;parent-child&lt;/strong&gt; relationship.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending Time With Kids&lt;/strong&gt; - I was lucky to born in prosperous business family. And we always had time for &lt;strong&gt;vacations&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;daily-fun-family-time&lt;/strong&gt;(like playing sports, watching movies together etc etc). I have good amount of fun memories with my parents which I am really happy about and would cherish them lifelong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom to Try&lt;/strong&gt; - My parents bought Computer when I was 10 year old doofus and having computer at that time was kind of a big thing. It is safe to say I was introduced with &lt;strong&gt;love of my life&lt;/strong&gt;. But at the same time I attended karate classes, music classes and many other classes, Eventually ended up with marrying computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-sure-there-are-many-other-great-things-that-my-parents-did-which-made-me-a-better-person-and-i-will-surely-update-them-if-i-could-recall-them-please-share-your-thoughts-and-views-on-the-same&#34;&gt;I am sure there are many other great things that my parents did which made me a better person and I will surely update them if I could recall them, please share your thoughts and views on the same.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;till-then-peace&#34;&gt;Till then Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>