<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 22:10:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Backup - Simple &amp; Cheap, without any plugins</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/wordpress-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 22:10:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/wordpress-backup/</guid>
      <description>It has been 3 months since I decided to implement my new eCommerce website on the WooCommerce platform which is a part of the Wordpress ecosystem. The site is live now and you go check it out - justspices.in It took me numerous nights and days to learn WordPress and take the site where it is now. Wordpress is kind of a double-edged sword. While it is easy to quickly deploy the site and integrate all the functionalities by choosing among a slew of plugins provided by the Wordpress community but at the same time, it is not so developer-friendly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memoirs of Corona Virus(2019) - Self-Isolation 🦠</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/quarantine-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 14:17:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/quarantine-updates/</guid>
      <description>The whole world is gripped by the fear of the Corona Virus. This virus is super-contagious and has symptoms ranging from mild-flu to dangerous life-threatening respiratory disease. As of writing this memoir 25th March 2020, no cure and vaccine has been discovered yet. Humanity&amp;rsquo;s best shot to contain the virus is to self-isolate and prevent the spreading of the virus. Many developed countries like Italy, Spain, Germany and even The US of America are shitting their pants to stop the spread of this virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madhya Pradesh Should be Your Next Travel Destination</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/madhya-pradesh-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 21:05:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/madhya-pradesh-rocks/</guid>
      <description>We recently made a road-trip to one of the densely populated tiger jungles of the world - Kanha and Bandhavgarh National Park. Both of which are located in Madhya-Pradesh(MP). MP is a state which you might have heard of but its not on anyone’s travel radar. We were looking for some National Park to explore in India and MP’s one seems to have good fauna of large cats especially Tigers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Programmer to Businessman</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/programmer-to-businessman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 22:36:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/programmer-to-businessman/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first of many posts to follow describing my journey from a programmer to a businessman. I have been a programmer for 10 years now, and recently I decided to join my family&amp;rsquo;s business full-time. I saw that transition coming at some point and I always envisioned myself how I will handle this transition. My current role in our business is to make it tech-enabled for smoother and human error-free operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019: Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/2019-year-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 21:52:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/2019-year-review/</guid>
      <description>2019 was easily the best year of my life so far. No, I didn’t start a company. No, I didn’t get married. No, I didn’t get a Job in Apple. But I still think 2019 was full of amazing learnings, travel stories, friendships.
When I was thinking of what format this blog should be in. The first idea that came to my mind was to just write down the most interesting events month-wise, but then I thought that would be too boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Vipassana Experience - Kathmandu, Nepal</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-vipassana-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 15:24:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-vipassana-experience/</guid>
      <description>It was 26th march 2018 around 11 am I was resting in zostel Kathmandu&amp;rsquo;s terrace. I was recollecting my thoughts on what has happened to me for the past 11 days. My mind was uncomfortably quiet, I was trying to distract it by various thoughts but again it would settle to my body sensations, I could hear the tiniest sound my body was making. It was feeling awkward to be back in the real world — a world full of noises, distractions, hate, and love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I gained from 2 10-days retreat (Vipassana)</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/vipassana-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:47:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/vipassana-benefits/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about Vipassana and want to up your meditation game. You should check it out (Official website)
It is a meditation technique originated in India and was rediscovered by Lord Buddha. You learn how to maintain a balanced and calm mind by observing your bodily sensations.
Vipassana so to speak is not everyone&amp;rsquo;s cup of tea. It&amp;rsquo;s quite intense and not one of those fantasized meditation retreat camps where everyone seems to be in zen mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Do This After Coming Back From Vipassana</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/you-should-do-this-after-coming-back-from-vipassana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/you-should-do-this-after-coming-back-from-vipassana/</guid>
      <description>So, you have completed the arduous 10-day Vipassana course and now you are all set to bear fruits of Vipassana in real life. But you know it, you can only benefit from the Vipassana practice if you consciously and continuously plug Vipassana in your everyday life. It would be unwise to assume that you will benefit from Vipassana by just completing the 10-day course and not following up on the practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising My Life via GTD  Getting Things Done  Week 2 - Here Comes Trello</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-2-here-comes-trello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-2-here-comes-trello/</guid>
      <description>This is my weekly write-up series on implementing GTD- Week 1
 So last week we talked about how I was groking the concepts of GTD by going through initial chapters of book.
I also did a retrospection on how I have been trying to manage my life and why I was failing till now. We will quickly go through my earlier practices which were not so fruitful in effectively managing my time —</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising My Life via GTD  Getting Things Done  Week 1</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Background Life can get overwhelming if you don’t try to organize it. It might also feel out-of-control when you want to do so much but only have 24 hours in a day. It’s very easy to see your day passing-by with no satisfactory outcome.
Being in fast-moving tech-world only compounds to the above-mentioned feelings. Hence, I am always on the lookout of how to manage my time and energy towards a fulfilling and a stress-free life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive a Corporate Shit Hole</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-to-survive-a-corporate-shit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-to-survive-a-corporate-shit-hole/</guid>
      <description>Life is hard and it’s harder when you have a shitty job. My choices landed me in a shitty job too. I like to call myself a survivor and I try to bring the best of every situation I am in.
Let’s start by defining what a CORPORATE SHIT HOLE and then you will know why it is not a good place to be. There are surely many type of Shit-holes but I have only experienced the one where people sit in front of computer and like to call themselves programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year at Springboard and I Couldn&#39;t Have Asked for More</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/one-year-at-springboard-and-i-couldn-t-have-asked-for-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/one-year-at-springboard-and-i-couldn-t-have-asked-for-more/</guid>
      <description>Sharing the story of how my life has changed over the last one year
9th May 2017, I didn’t know that after a year I will be in a position where I would be doing the most satisfying work and becoming the best version of myself. One step at a time!
Till that time I was working at Citi as a mobile developer and had reached a point where change was imminent as the work had become mundane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First UX Design Project  Lakshya</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-ux-design-project-lakshya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/first-ux-design-project-lakshya/</guid>
      <description>I was planning to learn UX design for such a long time and finally here is my first UX design project: Lakshya, an app which allows an user to manage their time easily by creating your goals and breaking them down into small tasks. UX design always interested me and being a front-end developer I think UX design skill will definitely come in handy.
I am really thankful for the Springboard for their wonderful course which has amazing curricullum and a very supportive mentorship programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Perception Matters</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/why-perception-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/why-perception-matters/</guid>
      <description>Perception is how we understand things after knowing about the situation/incident/event. Perception is basically the output of your thought process after analyzing the input which here is information about any event.
When I say event it can be any event -
 Person cutting you off in the traffic Osama bin laden killing people Someone having a baby You getting a promotion  Basically, anything which increases the entropy of universe can be called an event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Survived Despite Being Stupid</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I indulged myself in teaching basic mathematics to a 10-year old kid. While teaching him I realised that how quickly he was grasping stuff compared to how difficult that was for me. This incident led me realize that I was always a dumb kid, it always took me time to figure out stuff.
While I am not at peak of my career, but reaching where I am now for a dumb kid like me is a wonder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of People in a Team</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/types-of-people-in-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/types-of-people-in-a-team/</guid>
      <description>I watched The Office and felt it was really stupid, fun but stupid. I really thought it was all fictional and it was there for fun and totally unrelatable to real life. Ohh boy!! I was wrong! I was wrong by an arm’s length. There are types of people who you will find in your workplace that have unique and totally useless qualities. And the funny part is they like to talk about those qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gift Parents Can Give to Their Children</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer — I am no parenting expert, just putting out my thoughts.
Parenting is hard and for majority of parents it is their first time. So we all know what it is like to do a difficult task with inexperience. Apart from cleaning shit and pee stuff, the part where it really gets difficult is when you are supposed to impart your values to your offspring.
I think when you have kids you get some kind of “Power” you get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl&#39;s Guide to Arrange Marriage Dating</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</guid>
      <description>I have reached in my mid-20s and i am mostly surrounded by a lot of single girls and guys of same age. This age is perfect according to them for a wedding according to Indian parents. It’s like at this point of time parents feel like they have lost a sense of direction in life and have become unemploymed from the parenting job. It does not matter if the kid wants to get married or not all they want is some fun activity which will keep them busy for the next 1 year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Indian Adulthood</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</guid>
      <description>Adventures of Indian Adulthood Adulthood starts with a fun packed college life of 4 years or so, after that there are many options like getting a job, starting your own company, sitting on your dad’s shop or starting a JV to produce kids. Many of us end up having a typical job which involves mundane day-to-day task and it gets pretty boring. And it gets more boring if you don’t do any adventurous stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey With Javascript So Far</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/my-journey-with-javascript-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/my-journey-with-javascript-so-far/</guid>
      <description>I started learning javascript as a part of my 2016 new year’s resolution and that was one of the best decision I made in 2016. Since then I cannot stop thinking about Javascript. I am doing JS in office and home. I am overwhelmed by how a language built in 2 weeks took such an important place in the programming world.
Before embarking on learning something new(framework or language), I always like to read history about it, and know what was the reason it came into existence, what problem did it solved and read about people who built them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>