<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funny on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/funny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funny on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 15:50:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/funny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive a Corporate Shit Hole</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-to-survive-a-corporate-shit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-to-survive-a-corporate-shit-hole/</guid>
      <description>Life is hard and it’s harder when you have a shitty job. My choices landed me in a shitty job too. I like to call myself a survivor and I try to bring the best of every situation I am in.
Let’s start by defining what a CORPORATE SHIT HOLE and then you will know why it is not a good place to be. There are surely many type of Shit-holes but I have only experienced the one where people sit in front of computer and like to call themselves programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of People in a Team</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/types-of-people-in-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/types-of-people-in-a-team/</guid>
      <description>I watched The Office and felt it was really stupid, fun but stupid. I really thought it was all fictional and it was there for fun and totally unrelatable to real life. Ohh boy!! I was wrong! I was wrong by an arm’s length. There are types of people who you will find in your workplace that have unique and totally useless qualities. And the funny part is they like to talk about those qualities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Indian Adulthood</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</guid>
      <description>Adventures of Indian Adulthood Adulthood starts with a fun packed college life of 4 years or so, after that there are many options like getting a job, starting your own company, sitting on your dad’s shop or starting a JV to produce kids. Many of us end up having a typical job which involves mundane day-to-day task and it gets pretty boring. And it gets more boring if you don’t do any adventurous stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>