<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Survived Despite Being Stupid</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I indulged myself in teaching basic mathematics to a 10-year old kid. While teaching him I realised that how quickly he was grasping stuff compared to how difficult that was for me. This incident led me realize that I was always a dumb kid, it always took me time to figure out stuff.
While I am not at peak of my career, but reaching where I am now for a dumb kid like me is a wonder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gift Parents Can Give to Their Children</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer — I am no parenting expert, just putting out my thoughts.
Parenting is hard and for majority of parents it is their first time. So we all know what it is like to do a difficult task with inexperience. Apart from cleaning shit and pee stuff, the part where it really gets difficult is when you are supposed to impart your values to your offspring.
I think when you have kids you get some kind of “Power” you get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl&#39;s Guide to Arrange Marriage Dating</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</guid>
      <description>I have reached in my mid-20s and i am mostly surrounded by a lot of single girls and guys of same age. This age is perfect according to them for a wedding according to Indian parents. It’s like at this point of time parents feel like they have lost a sense of direction in life and have become unemploymed from the parenting job. It does not matter if the kid wants to get married or not all they want is some fun activity which will keep them busy for the next 1 year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures of Indian Adulthood</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 15:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/adventures-of-indian-adulthood/</guid>
      <description>Adventures of Indian Adulthood Adulthood starts with a fun packed college life of 4 years or so, after that there are many options like getting a job, starting your own company, sitting on your dad’s shop or starting a JV to produce kids. Many of us end up having a typical job which involves mundane day-to-day task and it gets pretty boring. And it gets more boring if you don’t do any adventurous stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>