<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life-Learning on Jiten Agarwal</title>
    <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/life-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life-Learning on Jiten Agarwal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 21:39:44 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jitenagarwal.com/tags/life-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Essential Business Tools</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/tools-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 21:39:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/tools-for-business/</guid>
      <description>I have been involved in developing a premium spices brand www.justspices.in for over a year now. This is my first stint at developing a business full-time after working as a professional software engineer for 4 years. Developing a business is fun and challenging. You face new challenges every day in execution while making sure you keep growing and find new avenues of revenue (that rhymed!) while keeping your values intact. Since I have been in this thing for a year now, I have developed some workflows that help me handle frequent chores error-free and smoothly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising My Life via GTD  Getting Things Done  Week 2 - Here Comes Trello</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-2-here-comes-trello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-2-here-comes-trello/</guid>
      <description>This is my weekly write-up series on implementing GTD- Week 1
 So last week we talked about how I was groking the concepts of GTD by going through initial chapters of book.
I also did a retrospection on how I have been trying to manage my life and why I was failing till now. We will quickly go through my earlier practices which were not so fruitful in effectively managing my time —</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising My Life via GTD  Getting Things Done  Week 1</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/organising-my-life-via-gtd-getting-things-done-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Background Life can get overwhelming if you don’t try to organize it. It might also feel out-of-control when you want to do so much but only have 24 hours in a day. It’s very easy to see your day passing-by with no satisfactory outcome.
Being in fast-moving tech-world only compounds to the above-mentioned feelings. Hence, I am always on the lookout of how to manage my time and energy towards a fulfilling and a stress-free life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Perception Matters</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/why-perception-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/why-perception-matters/</guid>
      <description>Perception is how we understand things after knowing about the situation/incident/event. Perception is basically the output of your thought process after analyzing the input which here is information about any event.
When I say event it can be any event -
 Person cutting you off in the traffic Osama bin laden killing people Someone having a baby You getting a promotion  Basically, anything which increases the entropy of universe can be called an event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Survived Despite Being Stupid</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/how-i-survived-despite-being-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Few days back I indulged myself in teaching basic mathematics to a 10-year old kid. While teaching him I realised that how quickly he was grasping stuff compared to how difficult that was for me. This incident led me realize that I was always a dumb kid, it always took me time to figure out stuff.
While I am not at peak of my career, but reaching where I am now for a dumb kid like me is a wonder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Gift Parents Can Give to Their Children</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/best-gift-parents-can-give-to-their-children/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer — I am no parenting expert, just putting out my thoughts.
Parenting is hard and for majority of parents it is their first time. So we all know what it is like to do a difficult task with inexperience. Apart from cleaning shit and pee stuff, the part where it really gets difficult is when you are supposed to impart your values to your offspring.
I think when you have kids you get some kind of “Power” you get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl&#39;s Guide to Arrange Marriage Dating</title>
      <link>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 15:50:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jitenagarwal.com/blog/girl-s-guide-to-arrange-marriage-dating/</guid>
      <description>I have reached in my mid-20s and i am mostly surrounded by a lot of single girls and guys of same age. This age is perfect according to them for a wedding according to Indian parents. It’s like at this point of time parents feel like they have lost a sense of direction in life and have become unemploymed from the parenting job. It does not matter if the kid wants to get married or not all they want is some fun activity which will keep them busy for the next 1 year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>